<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bikepacking on Jeroen Nyckees</title><link>https://jenyckee.github.io/tags/bikepacking/</link><description>Recent content in Bikepacking on Jeroen Nyckees</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 09:03:58 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jenyckee.github.io/tags/bikepacking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Biking the Annapurna Circuit</title><link>https://jenyckee.github.io/posts/biking-the-annapurna-circuit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 09:03:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://jenyckee.github.io/posts/biking-the-annapurna-circuit/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://jenyckee.github.io/img/nepal/DSC03673.jpg" alt="image"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During last summer I was looking for inspiration to do a long term mountain biking trip that would be challenging but pretty risk free at the same time. I had a time frame of three weeks in November so I started to look into possibilities when quickly my eye fell on a flight to Kathmandu. Nepal ticked off all the boxes I was looking for in my next trip, so without too much overthinking slightly nervous I booked the flights.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fatbiking in the Cairngorms</title><link>https://jenyckee.github.io/posts/cairngorms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 17:46:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://jenyckee.github.io/posts/cairngorms/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This winter in December I took a little escape from work to the Cairngorms national park in Scotland. I had been curious about riding a fatbike for quite some time and after seeing &amp;ldquo;Mountain Bikes and Bothy Nights&amp;rdquo; by Alastair Humphreys, a great video about bothy culture I thought this would be the perfect area to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;div
 style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"&gt;
 &lt;iframe
 src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/126241724?dnt=0"
 style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allow="fullscreen"&gt;
 &lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than that I Recently have been intrigued by steel bike frames. This for a couple of reasons. Steel bike frames are usually stiffer, tough heavier than aluminum frames. They are cheaper and more durable than carbon frames. And overall they just look cool.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>