<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Travel on Jeroen Nyckees</title><link>https://jenyckee.github.io/tags/travel/</link><description>Recent content in Travel on Jeroen Nyckees</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 09:03:58 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jenyckee.github.io/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Biking the Annapurna Circuit</title><link>https://jenyckee.github.io/posts/biking-the-annapurna-circuit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 09:03:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://jenyckee.github.io/posts/biking-the-annapurna-circuit/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://jenyckee.github.io/img/nepal/DSC03673.jpg" alt="image"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During last summer I was looking for inspiration to do a long term mountain biking trip that would be challenging but pretty risk free at the same time. I had a time frame of three weeks in November so I started to look into possibilities when quickly my eye fell on a flight to Kathmandu. Nepal ticked off all the boxes I was looking for in my next trip, so without too much overthinking slightly nervous I booked the flights.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>"They Work for Nothing"</title><link>https://jenyckee.github.io/posts/they-work-for-nothing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 15:50:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jenyckee.github.io/posts/they-work-for-nothing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Porto Moniz, a quiet little town on the most north eastern end of the island Madeira. In this little town one of the famous levada trails on the island finds its head. The trail takes you along an amazing irrigation channel leading water from high up in the mountains through the valley down to the people in this little town. After my girlfriend and I completed the trail we hitchhiked back to the little town and stayed in the local youth hostel. The hostel found itself next to a charming little church with a little square and drinking fountain in front. Next to the church there was a cafe similar to those you would see everywhere on the island. They would all have a few men inside, and one in the doorway, each quietly stirring their espresso and staring to whoever that is coming by.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>